GUANLI LIU

■ liuguanli22@gmail.com · **** (+61) 450075953 · **in** Guanli Liu

I'm a third year PhD student in the University of Melbourne. My research interest is using machine learning technology to solve database related problems, for example, index building. Prior to UoM, I as a senior researcher and developer in Baidu Inc. in Beijing, China.

EDUCATION

The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia

2019 – Present

PhD Candidate in Computing and Information System, expected December 2022

Northeastern University, Shenyang, China

2013 - 2015

M.S. in Computer Technology

Northeastern University, Shenyang, China

2009 - 2013

B.S. in Software Engineering

2 PAPERS

- Guanli Liu, Lars Kulik, Xingjun Ma, Jianzhong Qi. A Lazy Approach for Efficient Index Learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:2102.08081.
 - source code: https://github.com/Liuguanli/ModelReuse
- Jianzhong Qi (supervisor), Guanli Liu, Christian S. Jensen, and Lars Kulik. Effectively Learning Spatial Indices. PVLDB, 13(11): 2341-2354, 2020.
 - source code: https://github.com/Liuguanli/RSMI
- Yu Gu (supervisor), Guanli Liu, Jianzhong Qi, Hongfei Xu, Ge Yu, and Rui Zhang. The Moving K Diversified Nearest Neighbor Query. TKDE, 28(10): 2778-2792, 2016.

EXPERIENCE

The University of Melbourne

Aug. 2019 - Present

Tutor Comp90018 (Mobile Computing)

- Android development
- · Project guidance
- Assignment marking

Tutor Comp90041 (Programming and Software Development)

- Java development
- · Assignment marking

Baidu Inc. Beijing, China

2015 - 2017

Senior Researcher and Developer Android developer

Instant Messaging application development based on Android system. Key contributions are as follows:

- Message: Message recall, Message deletion, Red pocket Message, Contact Message
- Projects: QR code recognition, file transfer assistant, splash, global message search
- Voice assistant: Voice recognition SDK integration, send message, order meeting room

Neusoft Shenyang, China

Jun. 2012 - Sep. 2012

Software Engineer Java Web development

• Administrative system of the logistics

🗱 SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java > Python == C++
- Development: Java Web, Java, Android, SQL, LaTex, TensorFlow, PyTorch

\heartsuit Honors and Awards

	2016
performance appraisal in Baidu <i>Top 20%</i>	2016
Outstanding master student <i>Top 5%</i>	2014
3 rd Prize prize of American college students' mathematical modelling contest	2011
3 rd Prize prize of Google Android application development in China	2011

i MISCELLANEOUS

- GitHub: https://github.com/Liuguanli
- Languages: English Fluent, Mandarin Native speaker